# PRIYANKA SINGH

Email- priyankasingh30@gmail.com

LinkedIn- https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-singh-94014719/

GitHub- https://github.com/singhpri30

**Contact No**: 603-978-8279

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer experienced in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, APIs, Node JS, NPM, SQL Server. Experience in design, analysis, development and testing of user interface framework in various web-based applications. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills. Strong analytical and troubleshooting skills combined with quality work within the period. An excellent team player, experience working in agile team model.

#### **EDUCATION**

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE, 2020 University of New Hampshire, Portsmouth, NH

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (B.Tech.) IN Electronics and Communication, 2007, M.M.M.E.C Gorakhpur, India.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, APIs, AJAX, JSON
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux.
- > Backend: Node JS, SQL Server 2008, Oracle 10g.
- Software Testing: Automation Testing, Manual Testing, UAT, Back-end Testing (SQL), System Testing, User Acceptance Testing, Regression Testing, Functional/Integration Testing, End-to-End Testing, Mobile testing, Performance Testing and Defect Tracking.
- Test Tools: JIRA, ALM, TFS, Mantis.
- Automation Tool: QF-Test.
- Methodologies: Waterfall and Agile.

## **PROJECTS**

➤ The COVID-19 Tracker is an application that will assist organizations across NH in administering their screenings as well as provide their staff with important resources, communications, and data surrounding COVID-19.

# PRIYANKA SINGH

Email- priyankasingh30@gmail.com

LinkedIn- https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-singh-94014719/

GitHub- https://github.com/singhpri30

**Contact No**: 603-978-8279

- Responsibilities: To create COVID-Stats page. On COVID Stats page, the user can check covid-19 statistics in World, USA, and NH. The Covid statistics are represented in different formats. I used Chart.js, a JavaScript library to create charts.
- > Tools / languages used: HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma CSS framework, API, Ajax, Chart.js

#### Weather-Dashboard | Link to GitHub | Link to Deployed Project

https://github.com/singhpri30/Weather-Dashboard | https://singhpri30.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- > This project emphasizes the use of an API call and jQuery to make dynamic changes to an HTML document
- ➤ Responsibilities: Create a weather app with search input for user input, 3 API calls for Current Weather, 5-day Forecast and UV Index, 3 Separate cards with search history, current weather and 5-day weather. Local storage will save user history.
- ➤ Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, API, Ajax.

#### Code-Quiz | Link to GitHub | Link to Deployed Project

https://github.com/singhpri30/Code-Quiz| https://singhpri30.github.io/Code-Quiz/index.html

- ➤ This project emphasizes the use of HTML, CSS, JavaScript to create a time-based quiz with multiple choice questions.
- Responsibilities: Create a timer button that when pressed will start a reverse countdown and start the quiz., Start Quiz, Final Score and Highscores will be on appended HTML page
- ➤ Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap.

# Professional Experience

Portware India Pvt. Ltd. -Sr. Test Engineer: Oct 2012 – Apr 2014 (Clients-Carlson, Scotia Capital, RBC)

Coordinating with Development Team, Product Managers and Account Managers for deliverables

# PRIYANKA SINGH

Email- priyankasingh30@gmail.com

LinkedIn- https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-singh-94014719/

GitHub- https://github.com/singhpri30

**Contact No**: 603-978-8279

- Analyzing the requirements and raising clarifications to Product Managers and make the better understanding for the team members.
- Involved in preparing and reviewing Test Conditions & Test Cases and get it approved.
- > Involved in Smoke, Regression, Functional, Integration, GUI and Confirmation Testing.
- Involved in Test Execution, Identification of Defects, Defect Logging and reporting.
- Experience in Agile process -had been part of Sprint Estimations, daily Standup Meetings, weekly status and Monthly status meetings.
- Experience in setting up the test environment-Deployment of builds.
- Involved in Automation of test cases using QF-Test Automation tool.
- > Performed text execution on various environments e.g. Windows XP, Unix.

## Capgemini, India – Sr. Quality Engineer: Aug 2010 – Oct 2012 (Client-Serco UK)

- ➤ Involved in Requirement Understanding, Test Scenario Identification, Test Case creation, TC Execution and TC Review.
- Experience in BSD and FSD reviewing and providing feedback.
- Experience in Defect Management using TFS (Team Foundation Server-Microsoft)
- Experience in Creation and execution of test cases for functional and non-functional requirements.
- Experience in backend testing by executing SQL queries.
- Performed User Acceptance Testing at Client location Derby (United Kingdom).

# Cimcon Software India Pvt. Ltd.- V&V Engineer: Jan 2009 – Aug 2010 (Clients-TD Bank and InTotality Inc)

- Performed different types of testing on web-based applications.
- > Involved in requirement understanding and test scenario identification.
- > Experience in Creation and execution of test cases for functional and non-functional requirements.
- Experience in validating software applications in accordance with written software requirements and create/update defect reports for all issues found.
- > Experience in logging discrepancies found in application using Mantis bug tracking tool
- Performed Smoke Testing, Functionality Testing, Validation Testing, Regression Testing and Stress Testing, Usability Testing.
- Experience in Face book Integration Testing.